[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "level": "A1",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'молоко'",
        "options": ["milk", "salt", "tea"],
        "correctAnswer": "milk"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'соль'",
        "options": ["butter", "bread", "salt"],
        "correctAnswer": "salt"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'горячий'",
        "options": ["hot", "cold", "warm"],
        "correctAnswer": "hot"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'семь'",
        "options": ["five", "six", "seven"],
        "correctAnswer": "seven"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод числа 'два'",
        "options": ["one", "two", "three"],
        "correctAnswer": "two"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "level": "A1",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод буквы 'А'",
        "options": ["A", "B", "C"],
        "correctAnswer": "A"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'маленький'",
        "options": ["big", "small", "large"],
        "correctAnswer": "small"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'жёлтый'",
        "options": ["blue", "yellow", "green"],
        "correctAnswer": "yellow"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'Вашингтон'",
        "options": ["New York", "Washington", "Los Angeles"],
        "correctAnswer": "Washington"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод числа 'восемь'",
        "options": ["six", "eight", "ten"],
        "correctAnswer": "eight"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "level": "A1",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'папа'",
        "options": ["father", "mother", "brother"],
        "correctAnswer": "father"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'мама'",
        "options": ["father", "mother", "sister"],
        "correctAnswer": "mother"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'дружба'",
        "options": ["friendship", "family", "love"],
        "correctAnswer": "friendship"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'собака'",
        "options": ["cat", "dog", "bird"],
        "correctAnswer": "dog"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'кошка'",
        "options": ["cat", "dog", "hamster"],
        "correctAnswer": "cat"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "level": "A1",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'солнце'",
        "options": ["moon", "star", "sun"],
        "correctAnswer": "sun"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'земля'",
        "options": ["earth", "sky", "sea"],
        "correctAnswer": "earth"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'книга'",
        "options": ["pen", "book", "paper"],
        "correctAnswer": "book"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод числа 'десять'",
        "options": ["ten", "five", "eight"],
        "correctAnswer": "ten"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод числа 'три'",
        "options": ["two", "three", "four"],
        "correctAnswer": "three"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "level": "A1",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'стол'",
        "options": ["chair", "table", "sofa"],
        "correctAnswer": "table"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'стул'",
        "options": ["table", "chair", "bed"],
        "correctAnswer": "chair"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'окно'",
        "options": ["window", "door", "ceiling"],
        "correctAnswer": "window"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'дверь'",
        "options": ["door", "window", "wall"],
        "correctAnswer": "door"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'кровать'",
        "options": ["sofa", "bed", "desk"],
        "correctAnswer": "bed"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "level": "A2",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'Тихий'",
        "options": ["Atlantic", "Indian", "Pacific"],
        "correctAnswer": "Pacific"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'Марс'",
        "options": ["Mars", "Earth", "Jupiter"],
        "correctAnswer": "Mars"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'мёд'",
        "options": ["milk", "honey", "wax"],
        "correctAnswer": "honey"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'континент'",
        "options": ["island", "continent", "soup"],
        "correctAnswer": "continent"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'английский'",
        "options": ["english", "french", "spanish"],
        "correctAnswer": "english"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "level": "A2",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'Париж'",
        "options": ["Berlin", "Madrid", "Paris"],
        "correctAnswer": "Paris"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'авокадо'",
        "options": ["tomato", "avocado", "pepper"],
        "correctAnswer": "avocado"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'лев'",
        "options": ["tiger", "lion", "elephant"],
        "correctAnswer": "lion"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод числа 'двадцать пять'",
        "options": ["ten", "twenty", "twenty-five"],
        "correctAnswer": "twenty-five"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'зима'",
        "options": ["summer", "winter", "autumn"],
        "correctAnswer": "winter"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "level": "A2",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'письмо'",
        "options": ["letter", "email", "message"],
        "correctAnswer": "letter"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'солнце'",
        "options": ["sun", "moon", "star"],
        "correctAnswer": "sun"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'река'",
        "options": ["lake", "river", "ocean"],
        "correctAnswer": "river"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'горячий'",
        "options": ["cold", "hot", "warm"],
        "correctAnswer": "hot"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'птица'",
        "options": ["fish", "bird", "insect"],
        "correctAnswer": "bird"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "level": "A2",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'дом'",
        "options": ["house", "apartment", "building"],
        "correctAnswer": "house"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'зубы'",
        "options": ["teeth", "hair", "eyes"],
        "correctAnswer": "teeth"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'дружба'",
        "options": ["friendship", "love", "family"],
        "correctAnswer": "friendship"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'собака'",
        "options": ["cat", "dog", "rabbit"],
        "correctAnswer": "dog"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'машина'",
        "options": ["car", "bicycle", "plane"],
        "correctAnswer": "car"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "level": "A2",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'океан'",
        "options": ["sea", "ocean", "lake"],
        "correctAnswer": "ocean"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'гора'",
        "options": ["mountain", "hill", "valley"],
        "correctAnswer": "mountain"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'ресторан'",
        "options": ["restaurant", "cafe", "bar"],
        "correctAnswer": "restaurant"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'книга'",
        "options": ["book", "pen", "paper"],
        "correctAnswer": "book"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'река'",
        "options": ["lake", "river", "ocean"],
        "correctAnswer": "river"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "level": "B1",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'гепард'.",
        "options": ["cheetah", "horse", "elephant"],
        "correctAnswer": "cheetah"
      },
      {
        "question": "Заполните пропуск: 'I love to drink ___.'",
        "options": ["tea", "milk", "salt"],
        "correctAnswer": "tea"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какое слово не относится к другим?",
        "options": ["dog", "cat", "milk"],
        "correctAnswer": "milk"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильное завершение предложения: 'My friends often play ___.'",
        "options": ["soccer", "milk", "tree"],
        "correctAnswer": "soccer"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какое слово является антонимом к слову 'горячий'?",
        "options": ["cold", "warm", "hot"],
        "correctAnswer": "cold"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "level": "B1",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите перевод слова 'Токио'.",
        "options": ["Seoul", "Beijing", "Tokyo"],
        "correctAnswer": "Tokyo"
      },
      {
        "question": "Заполните пропуск: 'This is not my ___, it's his.'",
        "options": ["mobile", "table", "backpack"],
        "correctAnswer": "mobile"
      },
      {
        "question": "Заполните пропуск: 'I saw him ___ at the store.'",
        "options": ["yesterday", "tomorrow", "today"],
        "correctAnswer": "yesterday"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these sentences is correct?",
        "options": [
          "I like to read the book.",
          "I like the book to read.",
          "The book to read I like."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "I like to read the book."
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these words is a noun?",
        "options": ["funny", "smile", "dog"],
        "correctAnswer": "dog"
      }
    ]
  },

  {
    "id": 13,
    "level": "B1",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильный перевод фразы: 'I need to finish my work.'",
        "options": [
          "Мне нужно закончить работу.",
          "Я заканчиваю работу.",
          "Я закончил работу."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Мне нужно закончить работу."
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильное завершение предложения: 'He ___ to the cafe every day.'",
        "options": ["goes", "went", "would go"],
        "correctAnswer": "goes"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какое слово здесь лишнее?",
        "options": ["run", "swim", "fast"],
        "correctAnswer": "fast"
      },
      {
        "question": "Что означает выражение 'делать первый шаг'?",
        "options": [
          "start something",
          "finish something",
          "complicate the situation"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "start something"
      },
      {
        "question": "Заполните пропуск: 'Это очень ___ решение.'",
        "options": ["difficult", "difficultly", "difficulties"],
        "correctAnswer": "difficult"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "level": "B1",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Что будет, если вы добавите 'быстро' в предложение: 'He ___ runs.'",
        "options": ["quickly", "quickly runs", "quickly he runs"],
        "correctAnswer": "quickly runs"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильный перевод фразы: 'I will call you later.'",
        "options": [
          "I will call you later.",
          "I called you later.",
          "I will call you in the past."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "I will call you later."
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите синоним для слова 'умный'.",
        "options": ["stupid", "smart", "intelligent"],
        "correctAnswer": "intelligent"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какая из этих фраз является вопросом?",
        "options": [
          "You went to Moscow.",
          "Did you go to Moscow?",
          "You went to Moscow!"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Did you go to Moscow?"
      },
      {
        "question": "Заполните пропуск: 'We ___ to the park on the weekend.'",
        "options": ["go", "went", "will go"],
        "correctAnswer": "will go"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "level": "B1",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильный перевод фразы: 'I can't find my keys.'",
        "options": [
          "I can't find my keys.",
          "I can't find my key.",
          "I couldn't find my keys."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "I can't find my keys."
      },
      {
        "question": "Какое из этих предложений является правильным?",
        "options": [
          "We drank coffee in the cafe.",
          "We drink coffee in the cafe.",
          "We drank in the cafe coffee."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "We drank coffee in the cafe."
      },
      {
        "question": "Заполните пропуск: 'Did you ___ to the cinema on the weekend?'",
        "options": ["go", "went", "will go"],
        "correctAnswer": "go"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какой из этих вариантов соответствует утверждению: 'We are having dinner.'?",
        "options": [
          "We are having dinner.",
          "We had dinner.",
          "We are having dinner yesterday."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "We are having dinner."
      },
      {
        "question": "Какой из этих слов является глаголом?",
        "options": ["book", "swim", "dog"],
        "correctAnswer": "swim"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "level": "B2",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильный перевод фразы: 'She has been working here for five years.'",
        "options": [
          "Она работает здесь пять лет.",
          "Она работает здесь пять лет назад.",
          "Она работает здесь уже пять лет."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Она работает здесь уже пять лет."
      },
      {
        "question": "Заполните пропуск: 'If I ____ you, I would have helped.'",
        "options": ["were", "was", "am"],
        "correctAnswer": "were"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какое слово является синонимом слова 'делать'? ",
        "options": ["работать", "создавать", "использовать"],
        "correctAnswer": "создавать"
      },
      {
        "question": "Заполните пропуск: 'By the time he arrives, we ____ the work.'",
        "options": ["will finish", "finished", "will have finished"],
        "correctAnswer": "will have finished"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильный вариант: 'I ____ (know) him since we were kids.'",
        "options": ["have known", "knew", "will know"],
        "correctAnswer": "have known"
      }
    ]
  },

  {
    "id": 17,
    "level": "B2",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильное завершение предложения: 'If I had known about the meeting, I ____.'",
        "options": ["would attend", "would have attended", "attended"],
        "correctAnswer": "would have attended"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какое слово не подходит? 'summer', 'winter', 'quickly', 'autumn'",
        "options": ["quickly", "summer", "winter", "autumn"],
        "correctAnswer": "quickly"
      },
      {
        "question": "Заполните пропуск: 'She ____ (study) when I called her.'",
        "options": ["was studying", "is studying", "studied"],
        "correctAnswer": "was studying"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильный перевод фразы: 'We were waiting for the train.'",
        "options": [
          "We waited for the train.",
          "We will wait for the train.",
          "We waited for a train."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "We waited for the train."
      },
      {
        "question": "Что означает выражение 'стоять на месте'? ",
        "options": ["быть в процессе", "не двигаться", "двигаться быстро"],
        "correctAnswer": "не двигаться"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "level": "B2",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Заполните пропуск: 'If I ____ more time, I would have read the book.'",
        "options": ["had", "have", "will have"],
        "correctAnswer": "had"
      },
      {
        "question": "Заполните пропуск: 'He ____ (work) here since last year.'",
        "options": ["has been working", "worked", "works"],
        "correctAnswer": "has been working"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильное завершение предложения: 'I can’t understand why she ____ the decision.'",
        "options": ["has made", "had made", "make"],
        "correctAnswer": "has made"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какое слово не подходит? 'loudly', 'quickly', 'beautiful', 'carefully'",
        "options": ["beautiful", "loudly", "quickly", "carefully"],
        "correctAnswer": "beautiful"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильное завершение предложения: 'They have been working ____ they were young.'",
        "options": ["since", "for", "before"],
        "correctAnswer": "since"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "level": "B2",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Заполните пропуск: 'By next month, they ____ (finish) the project.'",
        "options": ["will have finished", "finished", "will finish"],
        "correctAnswer": "will have finished"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильный вариант: 'She ____ (learn) English for 3 years by the end of this year.'",
        "options": ["will have learned", "has learned", "learned"],
        "correctAnswer": "will have learned"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какое слово не подходит? 'rainy', 'snowy', 'walk', 'cloudy'",
        "options": ["walk", "rainy", "snowy", "cloudy"],
        "correctAnswer": "walk"
      },
      {
        "question": "Заполните пропуск: 'If he ____ more time, he would have finished the task.'",
        "options": ["had", "would have", "has"],
        "correctAnswer": "had"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильный перевод фразы: 'I have been studying for two hours.'",
        "options": [
          "Я учился два часа.",
          "Я учусь два часа.",
          "Я учу два часа."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Я учусь два часа."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "level": "B2",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Заполните пропуск: 'I would have gone to the party if I ____ (be) invited.'",
        "options": ["had been", "was", "have been"],
        "correctAnswer": "had been"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильный вариант: 'By the time you arrive, I ____ (leave) already.'",
        "options": ["will have left", "left", "will leave"],
        "correctAnswer": "will have left"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какое слово является синонимом слова 'быстрый'? ",
        "options": ["quick", "slow", "steady"],
        "correctAnswer": "quick"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильное завершение предложения: 'I’ve never seen such a ____ movie before.'",
        "options": ["interesting", "interest", "interests"],
        "correctAnswer": "interesting"
      },
      {
        "question": "Заполните пропуск: 'He would have helped you if he ____ (know) about the problem.'",
        "options": ["had known", "knows", "would have known"],
        "correctAnswer": "had known"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "level": "C1",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильное предложение: 'By the time they arrive, the meeting ____.'",
        "options": ["will start", "will have started", "starts"],
        "correctAnswer": "will have started"
      },
      {
        "question": "Завершите предложение: 'Had I known about the event, I ____ to it.'",
        "options": ["would go", "would have gone", "will go"],
        "correctAnswer": "would have gone"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какое из следующих предложений грамматически правильно?",
        "options": [
          "She has been studying since three hours.",
          "She studied for three hours.",
          "She has been studying for three hours."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "She has been studying for three hours."
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите слово, которое лучше всего подходит для предложения: 'Her answer was so ___ that I couldn’t believe it.'",
        "options": ["definite", "definitive", "definitively"],
        "correctAnswer": "definitive"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какой из этих вариантов является сложным предложением?",
        "options": [
          "He likes tennis, but she prefers football.",
          "He likes tennis.",
          "She prefers football."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "He likes tennis, but she prefers football."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "level": "C1",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Какова правильная пассивная форма предложения: 'The company will release the new product next month.'?",
        "options": [
          "The new product will be released by the company next month.",
          "The new product will release by the company next month.",
          "The new product was released by the company next month."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The new product will be released by the company next month."
      },
      {
        "question": "Завершите предложение: 'The manager insists that the employees ____ the project by Friday.'",
        "options": ["finish", "finished", "will finish"],
        "correctAnswer": "finish"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите наиболее подходящую фразу: 'The research conducted over the past decade ____ our understanding of the disease.'",
        "options": ["has revolutionized", "revolutionizes", "revolutionized"],
        "correctAnswer": "has revolutionized"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите слово, которое подходит по контексту: 'The researcher’s findings were ____ and contributed greatly to the academic community.'",
        "options": ["groundbreaking", "groundbreak", "groundbreaker"],
        "correctAnswer": "groundbreaking"
      },
      {
        "question": "В каком из следующих предложений есть ошибка?",
        "options": [
          "If I had known about the meeting, I would have attended.",
          "If I had known about the meeting, I would have attend.",
          "If I had known about the meeting, I would attend."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "If I had known about the meeting, I would have attend."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "level": "C1",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Какое предложение грамматически правильно?",
        "options": [
          "If he had worked harder, he would have passed the exam.",
          "If he had worked harder, he will pass the exam.",
          "If he worked harder, he would pass the exam."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "If he had worked harder, he would have passed the exam."
      },
      {
        "question": "Завершите предложение: 'They ____ the proposal by the time we return.'",
        "options": ["will have approved", "have approved", "had approved"],
        "correctAnswer": "will have approved"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите слово, которое подходит для предложения: 'The company will ____ a new strategy next quarter.'",
        "options": ["formulate", "formulates", "formulated"],
        "correctAnswer": "formulate"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите предложение, которое использует правильную форму условного наклонения:",
        "options": [
          "If you had asked me earlier, I would help you.",
          "If you asked me earlier, I would have helped you.",
          "If you had asked me earlier, I would have helped you."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "If you had asked me earlier, I would have helped you."
      },
      {
        "question": "Какое слово наиболее подходит для этого предложения: 'His speech was so ____ that everyone in the room was captivated.'",
        "options": ["eloquent", "eloquence", "eloquently"],
        "correctAnswer": "eloquent"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "level": "C1",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Какое предложение использует правильную форму сослагательного наклонения?",
        "options": [
          "It is important that he attends the meeting.",
          "It is important that he attend the meeting.",
          "It is important that he attended the meeting."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It is important that he attend the meeting."
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильную версию предложения: 'She _______ a proposal by the time you arrive.'",
        "options": ["has prepared", "will prepare", "will have prepared"],
        "correctAnswer": "will have prepared"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какой вариант правильно завершает предложение? 'The debate was so intense that ____ an immediate decision.'",
        "options": [
          "no one could reach",
          "no one could reached",
          "no one could reaches"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "no one could reach"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите предложение с правильной структурой: 'By the time the movie started, the audience ____ for hours.'",
        "options": ["has been waiting", "had been waiting", "was waiting"],
        "correctAnswer": "had been waiting"
      },
      {
        "question": "Завершите предложение: 'I wish I ____ more time to complete the project.'",
        "options": ["had", "have", "will have"],
        "correctAnswer": "had"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "level": "C1",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Какое предложение использует правильную форму будущего совершенного времени?",
        "options": [
          "By the time they arrive, we will finish the work.",
          "By the time they arrive, we will have finished the work.",
          "By the time they arrive, we finish the work."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "By the time they arrive, we will have finished the work."
      },
      {
        "question": "Какое из следующих предложений правильно?",
        "options": [
          "If I would have known about the event, I would have attended.",
          "If I had known about the event, I would have attended.",
          "If I had known about the event, I would attended."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "If I had known about the event, I would have attended."
      },
      {
        "question": "Завершите предложение: 'I would have helped you if I ____ about the problem.'",
        "options": ["had known", "knew", "have known"],
        "correctAnswer": "had known"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какой вариант правильно завершает предложение? 'If you ____ harder, you would have passed the exam.'",
        "options": ["studied", "had studied", "study"],
        "correctAnswer": "had studied"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите слово, которое подходит лучше всего: 'The lawyer’s argument was so ____ that the judge had no choice but to rule in his favor.'",
        "options": ["convincing", "convince", "convinced"],
        "correctAnswer": "convincing"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "level": "C2",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильную форму глагола: 'If I ____ the opportunity, I would have taken the job offer.'",
        "options": ["had known", "knew", "have known"],
        "correctAnswer": "had known"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какое из следующих предложений использует правильную структуру будущего совершенного продолженного времени?",
        "options": [
          "By this time tomorrow, I will be working on the project.",
          "By this time tomorrow, I will have been working on the project.",
          "By this time tomorrow, I will work on the project."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "By this time tomorrow, I will have been working on the project."
      },
      {
        "question": "Завершите предложение: 'He ____ at the company for five years by the time he retires.'",
        "options": ["will have worked", "has worked", "had worked"],
        "correctAnswer": "will have worked"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильную форму предложения: 'She will not go out unless she ____ her homework first.'",
        "options": ["finishes", "will finish", "finish"],
        "correctAnswer": "finishes"
      },
      {
        "question": "Завершите предложение: 'If I had more experience, I ____ for the promotion.'",
        "options": ["would have applied", "would apply", "have applied"],
        "correctAnswer": "would have applied"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "level": "C2",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Завершите предложение: 'By next year, the company ____ its new strategy.'",
        "options": ["will have implemented", "will implement", "implements"],
        "correctAnswer": "will have implemented"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какой из следующих вариантов правильно использует сослагательное наклонение?",
        "options": [
          "It is essential that he attends the meeting.",
          "It is essential that he attend the meeting.",
          "It is essential that he attended the meeting."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It is essential that he attend the meeting."
      },
      {
        "question": "Какой вариант правильно завершает предложение? 'Had I known how difficult the task was, I ____ it.'",
        "options": [
          "would not have accepted",
          "will not accept",
          "would not accept"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "would not have accepted"
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите слово, которое лучше всего подходит в предложение: 'The manager gave a ____ response to the client’s request, which helped resolve the issue quickly.'",
        "options": ["diplomatic", "diplomatically", "diplomacy"],
        "correctAnswer": "diplomatic"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какое предложение использует правильную форму прошедшего перфектного продолженного времени?",
        "options": [
          "She had been working on the report for three hours before she took a break.",
          "She has been working on the report for three hours before she took a break.",
          "She worked on the report for three hours before she took a break."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "She had been working on the report for three hours before she took a break."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "level": "C2",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Выберите правильное время глагола: 'By the time you arrive, I ____ the letter.'",
        "options": ["will have sent", "will send", "sent"],
        "correctAnswer": "will have sent"
      },
      {
        "question": "Завершите предложение: 'If I ____ known that the meeting was rescheduled, I would have attended.'",
        "options": ["had", "have", "would have"],
        "correctAnswer": "had"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какой из следующих вариантов содержит ошибку?",
        "options": [
          "He was wondering if I would join the team.",
          "He was wondering if I will join the team.",
          "He was wondering if I had joined the team."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "He was wondering if I will join the team."
      },
      {
        "question": "Какое предложение правильно?",
        "options": [
          "By the time I finish my report, I will be working for five hours.",
          "By the time I finish my report, I will have worked for five hours.",
          "By the time I finish my report, I will have been working for five hours."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "By the time I finish my report, I will have worked for five hours."
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите самое подходящее слово: 'The student’s ____ response demonstrated a deep understanding of the subject.'",
        "options": ["insightful", "insight", "insightfully"],
        "correctAnswer": "insightful"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "level": "C2",
    "isActive": true,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Какой из следующих вариантов является примером предложения третьего условного наклонения?",
        "options": [
          "If I had known about the event, I would have attended.",
          "If I know about the event, I will attend.",
          "If I had known about the event, I would attend."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "If I had known about the event, I would have attended."
      },
      {
        "question": "Завершите предложение: 'Had she known about the difficulties, she ____ the project.'",
        "options": [
          "would have never started",
          "would never have started",
          "will never start"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "would never have started"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какой вариант завершает предложение правильно? 'By the time the book was published, the author ____ for over a decade.'",
        "options": ["had been writing", "has written", "wrote"],
        "correctAnswer": "had been writing"
      },
      {
        "question": "Какое из следующих предложений грамматически правильно?",
        "options": [
          "I have been reading the book for two hours.",
          "I read the book for two hours.",
          "I had read the book for two hours."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "I have been reading the book for two hours."
      },
      {
        "question": "Выберите слово, которое лучше всего завершает предложение: 'The film was so ____ that it left a lasting impression on the audience.'",
        "options": ["captivating", "captivate", "captivation"],
        "correctAnswer": "captivating"
      }
    ]
  }
  
]
